No experience necessary.
Dungeons & Dragons: Honor Among Thieves is a adventure,
fantasy, comedy film directed by Jonathan Goldstein.
A charming thief and a band of unlikely adventurers undertake an epic heist to retrieve a lost
relic, but things go dangerously awry when they run afoul of the wrong people.
Edgin, played by Chris Pine.
Holga, played by Michelle Rodriguez.
Simon, played by Justice Smith.
Doric, played by Sophia Lillis.
Forge, played by Hugh Grant.
Xenk, played by Regé-Jean Page.
Dungeons & Dragons: Honor Among Thieves is a 2023 fantasy heist comedy film directed by Jonathan Goldstein and John
Francis Daley, who co-wrote the screenplay with Michael Gilio from a story by Chris McKay and Gilio.
Based on the tabletop role-playing game Dungeons & Dragons, it is set in the Forgotten Realms campaign
setting and has no connections to the previous film trilogy released between 2000 and 2012.
Starring Chris Pine, Michelle Rodriguez, Regé-Jean Page, Justice Smith, Sophia Lillis, and Hugh Grant, the film follows bard Edgin Darvis (Pine) and barbarian
Holga Kilgore (Rodriguez), who enlist a team of unlikely heroes to steal an ancient and powerful relic but come into conflict with evil forces.
Production went through various phases in development
since 2013, beginning with Warner Bros.
Pictures after beating Hasbro and Universal Pictures in a lawsuit over the film rights to the tabletop
game, before moving to Paramount Pictures, each with various writers and directors.
Goldstein and Daley were the final writers/directors, using elements from the
previous attempt by director Chris McKay and screenwriter Michael Gilio.
Filming began in April 2021 in Iceland and later Northern Ireland.
Dungeons & Dragons: Honor Among Thieves had its world premiere at South by Southwest on
March 10, 2023, and was released in the United States on March 31 by Paramount.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise for the performances of the
cast, the direction, visual effects, writing, score, humor, and tone.
It grossed $208.2 million worldwide on a $150 million
budget, making it a box office disappointment.
The film explores themes of platonic love, gang of
thieves, friends, dragon, role playing game.
The tone is lighthearted.